A Finding Aid to the Lee Nordness business records and papers, circa 1931-1992 (bulk 1954-1984), in the Archives of American Art AAA.nordlee
Archives of American Art
- Nordness Gallery, Inc. and Lee Nordness Galleries Art Advisory Section, Inc., bulk 1958-1982; circa 1938-1992; Series 1; 67.8 Linear feet Boxes 1-67, 117-119
  - Project Files, 1952-1990; 1.3
    - Corporate Files, 1965-1977; 1.3.7
      - National Endowment for the Arts, circa 1969 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - New Indian Art:USA, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Photography Project, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Portraits (Box 38)
        - Continental Can Company, 1970; 1974 (Box 38, Folder 12)
        - Cutler/Hammer, Inc., 1970 (Box 38, Folder 13)
        - General Mills, 1970; 1965 (Box 38, Folder 14)
        - Union Carbide Corporation, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - Proposed Corporate Projects, 1969-1970 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Projects, 1962-1990; 1.3.8
      Found is documentation of various projects including the Milton Hebald book, John Lennon's "Bag One" lithographs, Project Swiss project, the art collection of C.V. Starr & Co., and exhibitions with the United States Information Agency (USIA). Materials are varied and include correspondence, purchase records, shipping records and other miscellaneous business records.
      - Milton Hebald Book, 1970-1973 (Box 38, Folder 17-18)
      - Milton Hebald Book (Box 38)
        - Backers, 1967-1971 (Box 38, Folder 19)
        - Bills, 1967-1968 (Box 38, Folder 20)
        - Contract, 1970-1973 (Box 38, Folder 21)
        - Cutlines, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 22)
        - Text, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 23)
      - John Lennon (Box 38)
        - Advertising, 1980s (Box 38, Folder 24)
        - Correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 38, Folder 25)
        - Lithographs, 1980s (Box 38, Folder 26)
        - Sales, 1986-1989 (Box 38, Folder 27)
      - Project Swiss (Box 38)
        - Postcards, 1963-1965 (Box 38, Folder 28)
        - Purchase Records, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 29-32)
        - Warehouse, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 33)
      - C.V. Starr & Co., 1963-1969 (Box 38, Folder 34-35)
      - C.V. Starr & Co. (Box 38)
        - Art Gallery, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 36)
        - Artists, 1965-1969 (Box 38, Folder 37)
        - Fountain, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 38)
        - Hsu, T.C., 1968-1971 (Box 38, Folder 39)
        - Rudin, Paul, 1968-1969 (Box 38, Folder 40)
        - Shipping, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 41)
        - Suzuki, Toshi, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 42)
        - Tweedy, Gordon, 1969-1970 (Box 38, Folder 43)
      - United States Information Agency (USIA), 1969-1973 (Box 38, Folder 44-45)
      - United States Information Agency (USIA), Bills, 1972-1973 (Box 38, Folder 46)
      - United States Information Agency (USIA), Miscellaneous to Johnson Wax, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 47)
      - United States Information Agency (USIA) (Box 39)
        - Photographs for Tokyo Show, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Plastics Show, 1971-1973 (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Tokyo Exhibition, 1972-1973 (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - Tokyo Sculpture, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Business Records, 1955-1986; 1.4
    Business Records documents the day-to-day operation of the gallery, including gallery property and lease records, advertising, artist's biographies, corporate records, records related to the closing of Nordness' business entities, insurance policies, interoffice memos, inventories, mailing lists, and professional speeches and writings by Lee Nordness.
    - 236 East 75th St., Early Construction and Decor, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - 236-238 East 75th St., 1968-1974 (Box 39, Folder 6-8)
    - 252 West 38th St., 1977-1980 (Box 39, Folder 9-11)
    - 252 West 38th St. Flood, 1977-1979 (Box 39, Folder 12-17)
    - Ad Campaign, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Advertising, 1958-1968 (Box 39, Folder 19-24)
    - Artist Index Cards, circa 1959-1962 (Box 39, Folder 25)
    - Artist's Biographies, 1950s-1981 (Box 39, Folder 26-28)
    - Bernard's Working Hours, 1966-1968 (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - Census of Business, 1964-1972 (Box 39, Folder 30)
    - Clarke and Way, Bills, 1959-1961 (Box 39, Folder 31)
    - Corporate Records, 1965-1970; 1957-1958 (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - Corporate Records, Lee Nordness Galleries, Inc., 1986 (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - Craft Gallery (East 75th St.), circa late 1960s (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - Embossing Seal, circa 1958 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Equipment, 1958-1960 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Equipment Instructions, circa 1960-1964 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Fire Department, 1970-1971 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Gallery Closing, 1955-1965 (Box 40, Folder 5-9)
    - Gallery Supplies, 1964-1967 (Box 40, Folder 10-11)
    - Hahn Warehouse, 1964 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Insurance Policies, 1958-1968 (Box 40, Folder 13-16)
    - Interoffice Memos, 1965-1969 (Box 40, Folder 17-18)
    - Inventory, 1963-1966 (Box 40, Folder 19-21)
    - Leases, 1957-1971 (Box 40, Folder 22-25)
    - Lectures, circa 1971; 1969 (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - Mailing List, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 40, Folder 27-29)
    - New York Athletic Club, 1972-1973 (Box 40, Folder 30)
    - Lee Nordness Gallery Correspondence, 1979 January-February (Box 40, Folder 31)
    - Notes, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 32)
    - Office Supplies, 1965-1968 (Box 40, Folder 33)
    - One Man Shows, 1962 (Box 40, Folder 34)
    - Paintings Documentation, 1960 (Box 40, Folder 35)
    - Photos Ordered, circa 1964 (Box 40, Folder 36)
    - Show Schedule, circa 1964 (Box 40, Folder 37)
    - Speeches, Lee Nordness, 1960s (Box 40, Folder 38)
    - Staff Meeting, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Tax Deduction, 1964 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Telephone Book, 1950s-1960s (Box 41, Folder 3-4)
    - Time Payment Sheets, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Westhampton Beach, 1964; 1962 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Westhampton Gallery, 1961-1962 (Box 41, Folder 7-8)
    - Writings, Lee Nordness, circa late 1960s-1972 (Box 41, Folder 9-10)
  - Legal Records, 1950s-1979; 1.5
    This subseries contains correspondence and legal records for cases in which Nordness Gallery and Lee Nordness Galleries Art Advisory Section were involved.
    - Correspondence, 1967-1977 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Insurance Suit Against Von Cseh (1971-1979), circa 1974 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Ivonc Realty Lawsuit, 1968-1979 (Box 41, Folder 13-15)
    - Legal Actions, 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Legal and Financial Records, 1950s-1960s (Box 41, Folder 17-19)
    - Nordness Gallery, Inc. vs. Charles Bernoff, 1966-1967 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Roux, Vincent, 1957-1964 (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Financial and Sales Records, 1954-1992; 1.6
    Materials found include accounting ledgers, artist's bills and statements of accounts, bank statements, check stub books, consignment sheets, expense diaries, paid bills, received/returned sheets, sales invoices, shipping records, and tax records.
    - A/C, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - A/R, 1964-1966 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - Accounting Ledger, [Nordness Gallery, Inc.?], 1957-1959 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - Accounting Ledger, Nordness Gallery, 1958-1960 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Accounting Ledgers, 1961-1970 (Box 42, Folder 1-5)
    - Accounting Notes, 1965-1966 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Accounts Receivable Ledgers, 1959-1965 (Box 42, Folder 7-9)
    - Accounts Receivable Paid, 1964-1966 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Art Advisory Section Miscellaneous Income, 1980-1985 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Artist's Bills, 1959-1961 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Artist's Bills, Paid, 1962-1970 (Box 42, Folder 13-15)
    - Artist's Statements of Account, 1964 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Artist's Statements of Account (Box 42)
      - Aronson, David, 1961-1968 (Box 42, Folder 17)
      - Blaustein, Al, 1962-1965 (Box 42, Folder 18)
      - Collie, Alberto, 1964-1968 (Box 42, Folder 19)
      - Crawford, Ralston, 1962-1964 (Box 42, Folder 20)
      - D'Arista, Robert, 1963-1968 (Box 42, Folder 21)
      - Gibran, Kahlil, 1962-1965 (Box 42, Folder 22)
      - Gikow, Ruth, 1961-1965 (Box 42, Folder 23)
      - Guglielmi, Louis, Mrs., 1961-1965; 1968 (Box 42, Folder 24)
      - Hebald, Milton, 1962-1968 (Box 42, Folder 25)
      - Levi, Julian, 1961-1964 (Box 42, Folder 26)
    - Artist's Statements of Account (Box 43)
      - Liu, Kuo-Sung, 1967-1968 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Meigs, Walter, 1961-1968 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Williams, Hiram, 1962-1968 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Zerbe, Karl, 1961-1968 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Various Artists, 1961-1965 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Auditor Financial Statements, 1956-1964 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Bank Account Book, Guaranty Trust Co., 1958-1960 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Bank Correspondence and Statements, Morgan Guaranty Trust, 1954-1978 (Box 43, Folder 8-10)
    - Bank Statements, Morgan Guaranty Trust, 1959-1963 (Box 43, Folder 11-19)
    - Bank Statements, Morgan Guaranty Trust, 1964-1968 (Box 44, Folder 1-15)
    - Bank Statements, Morgan Guaranty Trust, 1968-1969 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Bank Statements, Citibank, 1981-1983 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Bills for Artwork Purchases, 1960-1964 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Canceled Checks, Seattle Trust, 1987-1992 (Box 45, Folder 4-6)
    - Cashbook, 1969-1981 (Box 45, Folder 7-8)
    - Check Stub Books, 1958-1961 (Box 45, Folder 9-16)
    - Check Stub Books, 1961-1964 (Box 46, Folder 1-10)
    - Check Stubs, 1986-1992 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Chemical Bank Loan, 1970-1971 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Commissions Due Artists Ledger, circa 1959-1969 (Box 46, Folder 13-14)
    - Consignment Sheets, 1961-1966 (Box 47, Folder 1-16)
    - Consignment Sheets, 1966-1969 (Box 48, Folder 1-6)
    - Consignments and Loans, 1962-1963 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1963; 1961 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Jose Montanes, 1964-1966 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Pink Copies, 1964 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Daybooks, 1955-1963 (Box 48, Folder 11-12)
    - Daybook, Nordness Gallery, 1964-1966 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Deposit Slips, Morgan Guaranty Trust, 1961 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Deposits, Citibank, 1977-1982 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Expense Diaries (27 diaries housed in a shoebox), 1968-1970 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Expense Diaries (6 diaries), 1973; 1970 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Expenses (Box 49)
      - European Trip (May 1963) (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - European Trip for Johnson Wax, 1963 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Nordness Gallery, 1959-1963 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - (To 1965), 1963-1964 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Travel, 1968-1972; 1959-1965 (Box 49, Folder 7-10)
    - Expenses, Travel, Lee Nordness, 1970; 1974-1975 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Expenses, Travel Around the World, Lee Nordness, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Expenses Paid, Lee Nordness, 1966-1973 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Financial Letter File, 1962-1964 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Financial Letters and Statements, 1963-1964 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Gross Profit Weekly Ledger, circa early-mid 1960s (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Loose Checks Unfiled, 1964; 1966 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Mail Returned, Former Staff, 1974 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1963-1968 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Paid Bills, 1958-1960 (Box 50, Folder 10-20)
    - Paid Bills (1961), 1959-1962 (Box 50, Folder 21-22)
    - Paid Bills (1961), 1959-1962 (Box 51, Folder 1-12)
    - Paid Bills (1962), 1960-1962 (Box 51, Folder 13-17)
    - Paid Bills (1962), 1961-1962 (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
    - Paid Bills [1963], 1962-1964 (Box 52, Folder 4-10)
    - Paid Bills [1964], 1963-1966 (Box 52, Folder 11-18)
    - Paid Bills, Art Advisory Section and Mr. X (1965-1966), 1963-1966 (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Paid Bills (1966), 1963; 1965-1967 (Box 53, Folder 1-5)
    - Paid Bills, 1966-1967 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Paid Bills (1967), 1963-1968 (Box 53, Folder 7-14)
    - Paid Bills (1968), 1967-1969 (Box 53, Folder 15-16)
    - Paid Bills, A-Z, 1969-1970 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Paid Bills (1969-1970), 1968-1972; 1965 (Box 54, Folder 1-15)
    - Paid Bills (1971-1972), 1969-1973 (Box 54, Folder 16-18)
    - Paid Bills (1971-1972), 1969-1973 (Box 55, Folder 1-4)
    - Paid Bills, Johnson Wax, 1968-1979 (Box 55, Folder 5-6)
    - Paid Bills, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Petty Cash, 1970-1972; 1963-1966 (Box 55, Folder 8-20)
    - Postal Meter Record Book, 1964-1966 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Receipts, European Trip [The Little Studio?], 1955 July-August (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Receipts, Bill Wallace, 1970 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Received/Returned Notebooks, Bill Wallace, circa 1959-1965 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Received/Returned Sheets, 1958-1965 (Box 56, Folder 5-18)
    - Received/Returned Sheets, 1965-1967 (Box 57, Folder 1-4)
    - Received/Returned Sheets, Miscellaneous, 1962-1963 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Sales Invoices, 1958-1963 (Box 57, Folder 6-17)
    - Sales Invoices, 1964-1971 (Box 58, Folder 1-6)
    - Sales Invoices, S.C. Johnson & Son, 1968-1970 (Box 58, Folder 7-10)
    - Sales Invoices, Masters, 1971-1991 (Box 58, Folder 11-13)
    - Sales Invoices, Mr. X and Miscellaneous, 1962-1968 (Box 58, Folder 14-15)
    - Sales Invoices, Paid Accounts Receivable, 1968-1969 (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - Sales Invoices, Miscellaneous, 1965-1971 (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
    - Savings Banks, 1972; 1968 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Shipping Receipts, 1959-1968 (Box 59, Folder 4-11)
    - Shipping Receipts, Freeslate, 1966-1968 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Taxes, 1958-1972 (Box 59, Folder 13-22)
    - West Coast Purchasers, 1962 (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - Williamsburg Savings Bank, 1976 (Box 59, Folder 24)
  - Inventory Records, circa 1958-1980; 1.7
    Records include inventories on index cards housed in nine shoeboxes, and two inventory ledgers. Headings for index card boxes were transcribed from original labels and may not accurately reflect the contents of the shoebox.
    - Art Advisory and Exhibition Section Inventory Ledger, circa 1968-1975 (Box 59, Folder 25)
      Oversized material housed in Box 119, Folder 1
    - Artists, Loose Index Cards, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 59, Folder 26)
    - Inventory Cross-off Ledger, 1970s-1980 (Box 59, Folder 27)
      Oversized material housed in Box 119, Folder 2
    - Index Cards (4 shoeboxes) (Box 60)
      - 140 East 81st St., circa 1960s-1974 (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - Artwork, Collection Unknown, circa 1958-1977 (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - LN Collection; Returned to Artists; Rico Lebrun, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - Loose Index Cards, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Meigs, Walter, Paintings at MM Warehouse, 1960s-1970s (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Index Cards (5 shoeboxes) (Box 61)
      - Returned to Artist, circa 1960-1974 (Box 61, Folder 1-2)
      - Returned to Artists (1968), 1960s (Box 61, Folder 3-4)
      - Zerbe, Karl, circa 1960s (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Oversized Art Advisory and Exhibition Section Inventory Ledger, circa 1968-1975 (Box 119, Folder 1)
      Oversized material from Box 59, Folder 25
    - Oversized Inventory Cross-off Ledger, 1970s-1980 (Box 119, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 59, Folder 27
  - Printed Materials, 1960-1980s; 1.8
    Printed Materials contains mostly newspaper clippings arranged by subject, as well as some press releases and postcards.
    - Architects, 1970s (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Avant Garde Art Groups, 1973-1978 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Buy [Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings], 1985 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1975 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Critics, 1969-1974 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Customs, 1974 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Dance, 1973-1977 (Box 62, Folder 7-9)
    - Nasty Reviews, 1960, undated (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Postcards, Miscellaneous, circa 1960s (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Press Releases, 1969-1972 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - To Read, 1980s (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbooks, circa 1940s-1980s; 1.9
    Found are scrapbooks for nine artists: Al Blaustein, Buckminster Fuller, Milton Hebald, Paul Horiuchi, Huchi-Chung, Zubel Kachadoorian, Harvey Littleton, Walter Meigs, and Karl Zerbe; and eight scrapbooks documenting exhibitions from 1959-1966. Artist's scrapbooks include photographs, slides, newspaper clippings, and exhibition catalogs. Exhibition scrapbooks contain newspaper clippings and exhibition catalogs. Additional exhibition scrapbooks documenting 1966-1974, and additional artist's scrapbooks are found in Series 2.
    - Blaustein, Al, 1950s-1960s (Box 62, Folder 14-20)
    - Exhibitions (Books 1-2), 1958-1960 (Box 62, Folder 21-23)
    - Exhibitions (Books 3-8), 1960-1966 (Box 63, Folder 1-12)
    - Exhibitions, Nordness Gallery (1958-1964), circa 1964 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Fuller, Buckminster, Synergy Exhibit Unpacking and Repacking Booklet, circa 1970s (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Hebald, Milton, circa 1940s; 1960-1970 (Box 63, Folder 15)
      Oversized material housed in Box 119, Folder 3
    - Horiuchi, Paul, 1958-1960s (Box 63, Folder 16-17)
    - Huchi-Chung, 1960s (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - Kachadoorian, Zubel, 1950s-1960s (Box 64, Folder 1-3)
    - Littleton, Harvey, 1960s-1970s (Box 64, Folder 4-5)
    - Meigs, Walter, 1950s-1960s (Box 64, Folder 6-7)
    - Meigs, Walter (1954-1967), 1950s-1970 (Box 64, Folder 8-13)
    - Meigs, Walter, Publicity, 1958-1971 (Box 64, Folder 14-15)
    - Zerbe, Karl, Artwork, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 65, Folder 1-4)
    - Zerbe, Karl, Publicity, circa 1953-1973 (Box 65, Folder 5-9)
    - [Loose Items] To Be Placed in Scrapbooks (Mr.X-5B), 1962-1975 (Box 65, Folder 10-11)
    - Miscellaneous Scrapbook Pages, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Oversized Scrapbook, Milton Hebald, circa 1940s; 1960-1970 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      Oversized material from Box 63, Folder 15
  - Photographic Materials, circa 1940-1980s; 1.10
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title. Slide boxes are housed at the end of the subseries.
    Nearly all of the materials found here are slides of artwork by various artists, especially artist Waylande Gregory. Slides for Art:USA, Objects:USA, and the Metromedia (Mr. X) art collection are also found here. Lists, boxes with notations, and other paper ephemera are scattered throughout the subseries. Unless otherwise noted in the folder heading, materials in folders are slides.
    - Art [Mixed Photographic Materials], circa 1980s (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - Art:USA: The Johnson Collection of Contemporary Paintings, 1960s (Box 65, Folder 14)
      Slides housed in Box 66, Slide box 1
    - Artists in Woodstock, New York [Photograph], circa 1940 (Box 65, Folder 15)
      Oversized material housed in Box 119, Folder 4
    - Barron, Mark, 1977 (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - Cooper, Bob, circa 1960s (Box 65, Folder 17)
    - Duncan, Tom, circa 1973 (Box 65, Folder 18)
    - Earl, Jack, To Identify, 1973 (Box 65, Folder 19)
    - Gallery Filing, 1972 (Box 65, Folder 20)
    - Gregory, Waylande, 1974 (Box 65, Folder 21)
      Slides housed in Box 66, Slide boxes 2-4
    - Gregory, Waylande
      - Categories, 1973-1974 (Box 65, Folder 22)
        Slides housed in Box 66, Slide boxes 5-6
      - Plates, 1974 (Box 65, Folder 23)
      - Rejects [Limited Circle?], 1973-1974 (Box 65, Folder 24)
        Slides housed in Box 67, Slide boxes 7-10
      - Slide Carousels 1-3, 1973-1974 (Box 65, Folder 25)
        Slides housed in Box 67, Slide boxes 11-12
      - Slides of Waylande and Yolande (slide box), circa 1968-1969 (Box 65, Folder 26)
        Slides housed in Box 67, Slide box 12
      - Slides To Be Mounted, circa 1974 (Box 65, Folder 27)
      - Unlabeled Slides, 1974 (Box 65, Folder 28)
    - Hultberg, Paul, 1972 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Mel, File, 1959-1974 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Mel, File and Identify by Williams, 1973 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Metromedia Collection (Mr. X), circa 1966-1968 (Box 66, Folder 4)
      Slides housed in Box 67, Slide boxes 13-14
    - Objects:USA, 1960s (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Objects:USA [Forms & Objects?], 1970-1974 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Objects:USA MCC (1200-1320), circa 1968 (Box 66, Folder 7)
      Slides housed in Box 67, Slide box 15
    - Petruchyk (A/C-O/C), circa 1972 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Siegel, Kathran, circa 1972 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Stewart, J., circa 1970s (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Tepper, Irv, Duplicate Slides, 1973 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Todd, Louise, 1971-1973 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified [Chinese] Ceramicists, circa 1972 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Unlabeled Slides (slide box), circa 1970s (Box 66, Folder 14)
      Slides housed in Box 67, Slide box 16
    - Various Artists, Artwork, circa early 1960s (Box 66, Folder 15)
      Slides housed in Box 67, Slide boxes 17-18
    - Various Artists, Artwork, circa 1963-1974 (Box 66, Folder 16)
      Slides housed in Box 67, Slide boxes 19-20
    - Various Artists, Artwork, late 1960s-1974 (Box 66, Folder 17-18)
    - Slide Boxes 1-6, 1960s-1974 (Box 66, Folder 19-24)
    - Slide Boxes 7-20, circa early 1960s-1974 (Box 67, Folder 1-14)
    - Oversized Photograph, Artists in Woodstock, New York, circa 1940 (Box 119, Folder 4)
      Oversized material from Box 65, Folder 15
- Lee Nordness Galleries Exhibition Section, Inc., 1938-1985; Series 2; 25.4 Linear feet Boxes 68-93, 120
  The records of Lee Nordness Galleries Exhibition Section, Inc. document the exhibition and sale of artwork through correspondence, artist's files, public relations materials, printed materials, photographs, sales invoices, and scrapbooks. Also found are corporation records, index cards for collectors and artists, and miscellaneous financial and banking records.
  This series is arranged as 5 subseries:
  2.1: Correspondence, 1961-1984
  2.2: Artist's Files, 1938-1983
  2.3: Business Records, circa 1960s-1970s
  2.4: Financial and Sales Records, circa 1958-1985
  2.5: Scrapbooks, 1951-1970s
  - Correspondence, 1961-1984; 2.1
    This subseries contains mostly business correspondence with museums, galleries, artists and clients regarding exhibitions and sales. Also found are legal records, printed materials, shipping records, and other miscellaneous records.
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by name or subject.
    - "A" Miscellaneous, 1968-1979 (Box 68, Folder 1-3)
    - "12 Afro-American Artists", 1967-1972 (Box 68, Folder 4-5)
    - The American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - American Artist Business Letter, 1981-1982 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - The American Federation of the Arts, 1965-1967 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Appraisals, 1971-1978 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Art Dealers Association of America, 1974 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Art in Embassies Program, 1968-1976 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - "B" Miscellaneous, 1968-1979 (Box 68, Folder 12-13)
    - Burlington Industries, 1967-1968 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - "C" Miscellaneous, 1968-1981 (Box 68, Folder 15-16)
    - Cables, 1969-1979 (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Cellar Gallery (Chicago), 1970-1971 (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Certificates of Ownership To Be Sent Out, circa 1969 (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - Charity Shows, 1968-1975 (Box 68, Folder 20-21)
    - Consignment Forms, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence (A-L), 1966-1975 (Box 68, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence Announcing Exhibition Section, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 24)
    - Craftsmen, 1968 (Box 68, Folder 25)
    - "D" Miscellaneous, 1968-1981 (Box 68, Folder 26-27)
    - Laura Dee Advertising, 1969-1974 (Box 68, Folder 28)
    - Dunning Letters, 1968 (Box 68, Folder 29)
    - "E" Miscellaneous, 1969-1982 (Box 68, Folder 30-31)
    - Exhibitions, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 32)
    - "F" Miscellaneous, 1968-1984 (Box 68, Folder 33-34)
    - Feist, Thomas, Photographer, 1968 (Box 68, Folder 35)
    - Fountains, 1967-1969; 1961 (Box 68, Folder 36)
    - Fountains, Taft Museum, 1969-1970 (Box 68, Folder 37)
    - Framing, circa 1970s (Box 68, Folder 38)
    - Freedman & Slater, 1968-1973 (Box 68, Folder 39)